Water
Earth
Fire
Air
My grandmather used to tell me stories about the old days
the time of piece
when the avator kept the balance between Water tribes, Earth kingdom,...
Fire nation and Air nomads
But that all changed when the Fire nation attacked
Only the avatar mastered all four elements
only he can stop the troops of firebenders
when the world needed him most, he vanished
A hundred years have past, and the Fire nation is nearing victory in the war
2 years ago, my father and the men of my tribe journied to...
...the Earth kingdom to help fighting against the Fire nation
leaving my brother and me to look after our tribe
some people believed the avatar was never reborn into the air nomads
and his psycho was broken. But I have lots of hope
I still believe that somehow, the avatar will return to save the world
-=AVATAR=-
The last airbender
-=Translated by YLX@HIT=-
Translate & Time Line: Tucity
Proofread:JOJO
Book one: Water
Chapter one: The boy in the iceberg
It's not getting away from me this time.
Watch and learn, Katara. This is I catch the fish.
Sokka, look!
Sh~, Katara, you gonna scared it away
Um, I can hardly smell it cooked
But Sokka, I caught one.
-Hey.
-Ha.
Why is it that everytime you play with magic water, I get soak
Ah,It's not magic, it's waterbinding
-and it is...
-yeah, yeah
ancient art, unique to our culture
blab,blab,blab
Look, I'm just saying that if I have weird power I keep my weirdness to myself
Here calling me weird.
I'm not the one who makes the muscles at myself everytime my see my reflection in the water
AHHH
Watch out!
Go left! Go left!
You call that left!
You don't like my steering. Well,
maybe you should waterbinder us out of the ice
-So it's my fault.
-I knew I should left you home
Leave to a girl to screw things up.
You're the most success amateur,not brained, I'm embarrassed to related to you
Ever since mum died, I've doing all the work around camp, while you've been playing a soldier
-Katara~
-I even wash all the clothes
Have you ever smell your dirty socks? Let me tell you. Let me!
-Katara, slow down.
-No. That's it. I'm done helping you!
From now on, you're on your own.
-OK, you've gone from weird to freakish, Katara.
-You mean I did that?
yep, congratulations!
He is alive, we have to help.
Katara, get back here. We don't know what that thing is.
Finally. Uncle, do you realize what this means?
-I want get finished my game.
-It means my search is about to coming to a end.
That light came from an incredible powerful source, it has to be him
It just a slice of your lights, we've been down this road before, Prince Zuko.
I don't want you to get too excited over nothing.
Please sit. Why don't you enjoy a cup of calming jessamin tea?
I don't need any calming tea, I need to capture the avatar.
Helmsman, head across for the light
STOP£¡
Stop it!
-I need to ask you something.
-What?
-Please come closer.
-What is is?
Will you go Panwing sailing with me?
Er, sure, I guess
-What's going on here?
-You tell us!
How did you get into the ice, and why aren't you frozen
I'm not sure.
Appa!
Are you alright? Weak up, buddy!
Hey, you're OK!
-What is that thing?
-This is Appa, my flying bison
Right.And this is Katara, my flying sister.
Don't worry. It will be washed out.
-So, do you guys live around here.
-Don't answer that!
Did you see that crazy ball of light, he probably try to signal to the fire, may be
Oh, ya, I'm sure he is the spy for the fire may be, you can tell by the evil looking in his eyes
-The pair annoyed one is my brother, Sakka. You never told your name.
-I'm...
I'm Aang.
-You just sneezed and flew 10 feet into the air.
-Really?It felt higher than that.
Ah, you're an airbinder.
-Sure I am.
-Jet light beams, flying bison, airbinders. I think I got midnight sun madness.
I'm going home to wash stuff, make sense.
You guys are stuck, upon. I can give you a lift.
-We love a ride, thanks.
Oh, no, I am not getting on that fluffy snore monster.
Are you hoping some other kind of monster will come along, and give you a ride home
... you know, before you freeze to death.
-Er...
OK. First time flyer, hold on tight.
Up and yep yep!
Come on,Appa. Yep, yep!
Wow, that was truely amazing!
Appa is just tired, a little rest and he will be the throne in the sky. You will see.
-Why are you smiling at me like that?
-Oh, I was smiling?
I'm going to bed now.
Yep, a man needs his rest.
Prince Zuko, you need some sleep.
Even if you're right, and the avatar is alive, you won't find him.
Your father, grand father, and great grand father all tried and failed.
Because their honor didn't hint the avatar 's capture, mine dose.
This covered hundred years, and hiding are over.
-Hey.
-What are you thinking about?
-I guess I was wandering...
you're being a airbinder and, or if you have any idea what happend to the avatar
Er, no, I didn't know him. I mean I knew people that knew him. But I didn't. Sorry
-OK, just curious. Good night.
-Sleep tight.
Aang, Aang, wake up!
It's OK. We are in the village now. Come on and get ready.Everyone is waiting to meet you.
Aang, this is the entire village. Entire village, Aang.
Er, why are they all looking at me like that?
-Did Appa sneeze on me?
-Well, no one has seen a airbinder in a 100 years.
We thought they were extinct until my grand daughter and grand son found you.
-Extinct?
-Aang, this is my grand mother.
Call me Gran Gran.
What is this? A weapon. You can't stab anything with this.
It's not for stabing, it's for airbinding.
Magic, do it again.
Not magic, airbinding. It lets me control the air current around my glander(*) and fly
You know, last time I checked, humans can't fly
Check again.
It's amazing!
Oh, my watch tower!
That was amazing!
Great, you're an airbinder, Katara is a waterbinder, together you can just waste time all day long.
-You're a waterbinder.
-Well, sort of, not yet.
Alright, no more playing. Come on, Katara, you have trouse.
I told you he was the real thing, Gran Gran. I finally found an airbinder to teach me.
-Katara, try not put all your hopes in this boy.
-But he is special, I can tell.
I sense he is filled with much them
See, ... my tongue... is...can look like this
Again!
No, power in firebinding comes from the breath, not the muscles.
The breath becomes energy in the body, the energy extends past your limbs and becomes fire.
-Get right this time.
-Enough.
I've been drilling this sequence all day, teach me the next set, I'm more than ready.
-No, you're inpatient. You have to master your basics.
Drill it again.
The say just tell us the avatar is the last airbinder, he must be over 100 years old by now.
He had a century to master the 4 elements, I'll need more than basic firebinding to defeat him.
You will teach me the advanced set.
Very well, but first I must finish my roast duck.
Now, man, it's important that you show no fear when you face a firebinder.
In the water tribe, We fight to the last man standing.
For with our courage, all we can call ourselves men.
-I gotta pee.
-Listen, until your father return from the war, there accounting you to the man in the strib.
And that means no party breaks.
-But I really gotta go.
-OK, who else to go?
Have you seen Aang? Gran Gran said he dispeared over an hour ago.
Wow, everyting freezes in the air
Katara.Get him out of here. This lesson is for warriors only.
Stop, stop it right now.
What's wrong with you. We don't have time for fun and games with the war going on.
What war? What are you talking about?
-You're kiding, right?
-Pangwing!
He is kiding, right?
-Aang?
-Hey, come on, little guy!
Wanna go a flating?
I'll weave as animals, KA KA
Aang, I will help you catch a Panwing if you teach me waterbinding.
You got a deal. Just one little problem, I'm an airbinding, not a waterbinding.
Is there someone in your tribe can teach you?
No, you're looking at the only waterbinder in the whole south pole.
This is not right. A waterbinder needs to ask water.
What about the north pole, there's another water tribe over there, right?
-Maybe there waterbinder can teach you.
-May be.
But we have not contected the sister-tribe for a long time.
It's not exactly turn right at the second leisure, it's on the other side of the world.
But you forget. I have a flying bison. Appa and I can personly fly you to the north pole.
-Katara, we gonna find you a master.
-That's... I mean, I don't know.
I've never leave my home before.
Well, you think about it. But at mean time, can you teach me how to catch one of these Panwings.
OK. Listen closely my young pupil. Catch Panwing is an ancient and secret art. Observe.
-I haven't done this since I was kid.
-We still are kids.
Wow, what is that?
A fire nabe ship and a very bad memory for my people.
Aang, stop. We're not aloud to go near it. The ship could be booby trap.
If you want to be a binder, you have to let go off fear.
This ship has hang to my tribe since my Gran Gran was a little girl. It was the part of Fire nation's first attacks.
OK. Backup. I have friends all over the world, even in the Fire nation. I have never seen any wars.
-Aang. How long were you in that iceberg.
-I don't know. A few days, maybe.
-I think it was more like 100 years.
-What? That's impossible. Do I look like a 120-year man to you?
Think about it. The war is a century old. You don't know about it because...
somehow you were in there that whole time. That's the only explaination.
-100 years. I can't believe it.
-I'm sorry, Aang. Maybe somehow there is a brightsight to all this.
-I dig it to meet you.
-Come on. Let's get out of here.
Aang, let's head back. This place is crapy.
What that you said about booby traps?
Hold on tight.
The last airbinder. Quite out gel for * age.
Wake my uncle. Tell him I found the avatar, ...
...as well as his hiding place.
To be continued.